<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on eddie_cosma</title>
    <link>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on eddie_cosma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Eddie Cosma</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eddiecosma.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting between 10– and 11– digit NDCs</title>
      <link>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/converting-between-10-and-11-digit-ndcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/converting-between-10-and-11-digit-ndcs/</guid>
      <description>Background National Drug Code, or NDC, numbers are 10-digit unique identifiers for human drug products marketed in the United States. Each NDC number comprises three sequential sections that describe different aspects of a drug product:
   Component Length Assigned by Describes     Labeler code 4–5 digits FDA manufacturer, repackager, or relabeler of the product   Product code 3–4 digits labeler dosage characteristics of the drug (including strength and formulation)   Package code 1–2 digits labeler package type and size of the product    You may have noticed that each of the different components of an NDC number is variable in length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Excel to access RxNorm</title>
      <link>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/using-excel-to-access-rxnorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/using-excel-to-access-rxnorm/</guid>
      <description>Background Let&amp;rsquo;s say you work in an institutional pharmacy that performs a physical inventory every December. This year, you discover there&amp;rsquo;s a large discrepancy between the value of your current medication stock compared to the value of last year&amp;rsquo;s stock. Apparently, some of the data on the handheld computers you use to perform inventory became corrupted before everything could be compiled into one large Excel file. Now you&amp;rsquo;re missing a few hundred line items, the end of the year is coming up, and Accounting is breathing down your neck.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
