<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>eddie_cosma</title><link>https://eddiecosma.com/</link><description>Recent content on eddie_cosma</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Eddie Cosma</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eddiecosma.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disclaimer for @OHVaxStats</title><link>https://eddiecosma.com/disclaimer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eddiecosma.com/disclaimer/</guid><description>General The Twitter post content (the &amp;ldquo;Content&amp;rdquo;) provided by this account is for educational purposes only. It is not intended to substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment. Effort is made to ensure data accuracy and reliability, however no guarantee can be made to this effect.
THE CONTENT IS PROVIDED &amp;ldquo;AS IS&amp;rdquo;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://eddiecosma.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eddiecosma.com/projects/</guid><description>Medcopia drug shortage alerts Email alert system that tracks changes to the ASHP drug shortages list and sends messages to users whenever a drug is added to or removed from the list. Written in Python.
Website: https://medcopia.cosmanaut.com/ GitHub: https://github.com/eddie-cosma/medcopia Ohio COVID vaccine statistics library Python library for accessing Ohio Department of Health statistics on daily COVID-19 vaccinations. Open source on Github. Used to develop a Twitter bot (@OHVaxStats) that posts vaccination statistics daily.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://eddiecosma.com/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eddiecosma.com/about/</guid><description>I am a Pharmacy Informatics Specialist at MetroHealth Medical Center in Cleveland, OH. I graduated from the College of Pharmacy at The University of Toledo and completed a PGY-1 Pharmacy Practice residency at University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center. Outside of pharmacy, I enjoy reading fiction and photographing anything and everything.
Curriculum vitae My CV is available for review here: Edward_Cosma-CV.pdf.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://eddiecosma.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eddiecosma.com/contact/</guid><description>For professional correspondence, you can reach me on LinkedIn.</description></item><item><title>Converting between 10– and 11– digit NDCs</title><link>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/converting-between-10-and-11-digit-ndcs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/converting-between-10-and-11-digit-ndcs/</guid><description>Background National Drug Code, or NDC, numbers are 10-digit unique identifiers for human drug products marketed in the United States. Each NDC number comprises three sequential sections that describe different aspects of a drug product:
Component Length Assigned by Describes Labeler code 4–5 digits FDA manufacturer, repackager, or relabeler of the product Product code 3–4 digits labeler dosage characteristics of the drug (including strength and formulation) Package code 1–2 digits labeler package type and size of the product You may have noticed that each of the different components of an NDC number is variable in length.</description></item><item><title>Using Excel to access RxNorm</title><link>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/using-excel-to-access-rxnorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eddiecosma.com/posts/using-excel-to-access-rxnorm/</guid><description>Background Let&amp;rsquo;s say you work in an institutional pharmacy that performs a physical inventory every December. This year, you discover there&amp;rsquo;s a large discrepancy between the value of your current medication stock compared to the value of last year&amp;rsquo;s stock. Apparently, some of the data on the handheld computers you use to perform inventory became corrupted before everything could be compiled into one large Excel file. Now you&amp;rsquo;re missing a few hundred line items, the end of the year is coming up, and Accounting is breathing down your neck.</description></item></channel></rss>